# MOHAMMAD MOTLAQ ALQAHTANI

<u>Change Management Officer</u> Senior Registered Respiratory Therapist Alrafieah, Riyadh, KSA

Cell# +966503899512

Email: mohammad.rrt@gmail.com

DOB: 19/01/1987 Marital Status: Married

# Summary of Qualifications

I'm a person who is an **advocate to change management** and I'm practicing it with all change initiatives done under my Administration when it's applicable. I am a highly motivated person who never stopped learning and gaining the required skills and knowledge to keep my professionalism at its highest level. Aware of work policies and procedures and comply with them as part of commitments.

Since October 2021 I have been delegated as **Change Management Officer** under the Executive Administration of Cooperate Communication and Change Management in addition to my assigned position as **Chairperson of the Respiratory Ambulatory Care Department**.

As a Change management officer who knows different change management methodologies, <u>currently</u>, <u>I'm working on making a change management plan for Human Capital and Healthcare Delivery under the Riyadh Cluster 2 to realize the HealthCare Transformation</u>.

Since 2009 I have gradually gained the required leadership skills and knowledge that give me chance to be promoted starting from regular staff as a Respiratory Therapist till I have become a Chairperson.

I have been working with manpower-related issues since I was assigned as an operation supervisor in the Respiratory Care Administration in March 2015. I was responsible for scheduling, planning vacations, and managing the manpower in the Respiratory Care Administration.

## **CURRENT JOB TITLE:**

- Change Management Officer at King Fahad Medical City.
- Senior Registered Respiratory Therapist at King Fahad Medical City- Riyadh

## **CURRENT POSITION TITLE:**

• **Chairperson** of Respiratory Ambulatory Care Department (May 2020 – Present).

## **Education:**

- <u>Professional Master in Cooperate Communication Management</u>, Roma Business School (Online, Oct 2021

   Sept 2022)
- Master's degree of Sciences in Health Sciences, The Byrdine F. Lewis School of Nursing and Health Professions, Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA. 2014
- Certificate Program in Respiratory Care (Loma Linda University) Riyadh 2010
- Bachelor's degree of Sciences in Respiratory Care, College of Applied Medical Sciences, King Faisal University. 2009

## **Licensure/Credentials**

- PROSCI® (Change Management Certificate)
- CCMP (Certified Change Management Professional) by Association of Change Management Professionals (ACMP)
- CRT (Certified Respiratory Therapist) From National Board for Respiratory Care- U.S.
- RRT (Registered Respiratory Therapist) From National Board for Respiratory Care- U.S.
- NPS (Neonatal Pediatric Specialist) From National Board for Respiratory Care- U.S.
- ACCS (Adult Critical Care Specialist) From National Board for Respiratory Care- U.S.
- CPFT (Certified Pulmonary Function Technologist) From National Board for Respiratory Care- U.S.
- Professional Accreditation Certification from Saudi Commission for Health Specialties.
- BLS (Basic Life Support).
- ACLS (Advanced Cardiac Life Support)
- PALS (Pediatric Advanced Life Support)
- Intubation Rotation course during the internship at KFMC in 2009.

## Experience:

- Change Management Officer (Oct. 2021-present)
- **Chairperson** of Respiratory Ambulatory Care Department (May 2020 Present)
- Head of Respiratory Care Emergency Room Section (July 2015- May 2020)
- Operational Supervisor (March 2015- July 2019).
- **AICU- Senior Respiratory Therapist** (Jan 2013- Aug 2013)
- **PICU- Senior Respiratory Therapist.** (Feb 2012- Dec 2012)
- Respiratory Therapist I (Aug 2009- Oct 2010).
- Work as ICU In-Charge RT who is responsible for all the ICUs after working hours, night, and weekends.
- Work as Respiratory Care Educator for Home Care Patients who educate the patient about their respiratory equipment before discharge.
- Assist the consultant with Bronchoscopy.
- Member of RCRSCG (Respiratory Care Research Subcommittee Group).
- Work in (Adult ICU) (PICU) (NICU)-(CCU)-(ACVICU) (PCVICU).
- Internship at King Fahad Medical City- Riyadh. (Aug 2008 Aug 2009).

#### Courses:

- Change management course by Excellence institution, Riyadh, Nov 2019.
- Crucial Accountability Course, Riyadh, OCT. 2018.
- Crucial Conversation Course, Riyadh, April 2018
- Six Sigma course (yellow belt).
- Servo-I MAQUTE NAVA training in Dubai, UAE (March 2015)
- Airway Management Course by CHEST at King Fahad Medical City (23-24 Jan 2013)
- Servo-i MAQUETTE training in Solana, Sweden (26-27 March 2012).
- Comprehensive Respiratory Care Practice- NBRC Board Review at Dallah Hospital 12-15\06\2010
- 5th Neonatal and Pediatric Mechanical Ventilation Course which was held from 29th to 30th of December 2007.
- 7th Adult Mechanical Ventilation Course which held from 26th to 28th of May 2007.
- Summer Training Program in Respiratory Department in King Abdulaziz Medical City from 23 June to 31 July 2007.

#### **Conferences and Workshops:**

- As a speaker at Alhabib International Critical Care Conference. Riyadh, 2022
- **As a speaker in** 'from Intubation to Mechanical Ventilation COVID-19 Management Included' at King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh, 2019
- As a speaker in '1st Respiratory Care Scientific Conference' at King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh, 2019
- As a speaker in '2nd Respiratory Care Symposium' at King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh, 2018
- As a speaker in 'Respiratory Care Scientific Symposium' at King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh, 2017
- As a speaker in 'From Intubation to Mechanical Ventilation: A Simulation Course', KFMC, Riyadh, April 2016.
- ECMO extensive training course, Tennessee, USA, 2019
- AARC Congress 2018, Las Vegas, USA
- The Gulf Thoracic Congress 2015
- AARC Congress 2013, Anaheim, CA, USA.
- The 4th Saudi Society for Respiratory Care's Scientific Conference at Dammam University (23-25 May 2011)
- The Gulf Thoracic Congress 2011 (16-19 March 2011).
- 1st Saudi International Respiratory Care Conferences which were held on 19th 21st of February 2008.
  - Proportional Assist Ventilation Workshop.
  - o Polysomnography workshop.
- 3rd Respiratory Care Symposium on Pulmonary Function Testing: Basic and Advanced which was held on November 22, 2006.
- 6th Annual Scientific Conference of the Saudi Thoracic Society in collaboration with the Saudi Critical Society and Saudi Advisory Group for Pulmonary Hypertension which was held on 18 20 of March 2008.

## Skills:

- Research
- Microsoft (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)
- Internet.
- Reading.